<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Englishes on hieudoan7</title>
    <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Englishes on hieudoan7</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 16:08:55 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Take_english</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/take_english/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 16:08:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/take_english/</guid>
      <description>source: https://www.talkenglish.com/
I. English Speaking Basic I  I&amp;rsquo;m I&amp;rsquo;m in/at/on  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words In Reality</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/word_usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 14:17:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/word_usage/</guid>
      <description>1. In relation to in relationship to something, in the context of Ex:
 The drugs is being studied for possible beneficial effects in relation to migraine headaches. She checked the map to see where Miami in relation to Orlando (~ compared with) I have several comments to make in relation to the subject at hand. (~ reference to)  2. in terms of talk about something then clarifying a specific perspective</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grammar Worth Noting</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/grammar_note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 10:13:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/grammar_note/</guid>
      <description>1. Be of + N The constructor Be Of + Noun is virtually the same as Be + Adj except it sounds more formal. You can think of it as to be of a certain class or of a certain type. Among the best ~ Of the best Ex: The book is of interest Can I be of any help?
2. Was/Were + Doing 3. It vs That(This)  both are pronoun   IT: without nuance This/that: with nuance (emphasis), also repalce whole phrase/sentence  4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hieu&#39;s Corpus</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/hieuscorpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 21:56:33 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/hieuscorpus/</guid>
      <description>Ronaldo Interview
 Surely that must concern you You have never revealed and I don&amp;rsquo;t think you ever intent to reveal The thing that occurred to me while watching the film was You don&amp;rsquo;t owe the world an explanation but you obviously feel that you would owe him the truth Do you ever worry about &amp;hellip; How do you approach that If you are in my shoes, what you gonna do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Council Learning English for teen</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/britishcteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 16:01:57 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/britishcteen/</guid>
      <description>I. Vocabulary 1. Accessories  rucksack scarf bracelet earrings glasses What accesories do you wear? I don&amp;rsquo;t usually wear many accessories. In my daily work, I wear my rucksack to carry my laptop. I also wear a watch on my left wrist, a hap and sunglassess if I need to go outside. I also wear a belt in case my trousers is quite big. In the winter, I wear the scarf to keep my body warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESL - Listening Series</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/esl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 10:17:44 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/esl/</guid>
      <description>Intermediate 1. A Student Credit Card source: https://www.esl-lab.com/intermediate/credit-cards/
 quiz -&amp;gt; plural: quizzes shred Come over (phrasal verb)
-&amp;gt; to visit someone&amp;rsquo;s home Drop off That is the least I can do Over (preposition) -&amp;gt; during spend yourself in a hole impulse (n) a sudden desire pay thing back  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part of Speech and its function</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/partofspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 15:40:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/partofspeech/</guid>
      <description>There are 9 basic types called &amp;ldquo;parts of speech&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;word classes&amp;rdquo;
 Verb Noun A noun can perform any of the following five functions:   Subject of a verb Object of a verb Complement of a verb (subject complement) Object of a preposition Be in apposition to another noun  Pronoun   same as noun  Adjective   noun modifier  Adverb
https://dictionary.cambridge.org/grammar/british-grammar/adverbs-functions   modifying a verb modifying an adjective modifying another adverb modifying a noun phrase modifying the whole clause modifying the whole sentence  Determiner   determine the noun (a/an the my)  Preposition https://studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Reading] 01 - 7 Incredible Resources of English Reading</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/reading_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:17:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/reading_01/</guid>
      <description>FluentU - 7 Incredible Resources Designed to Help You Learn English Reading link: https://www.fluentu.com/blog/english/learn-english-reading-4/ 1. The more that you read, the more things you will know
-&amp;gt; The more + S V (simple tense), the more S + will + V.
2. Most people are familiar with St
3. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more right!
4. The fact is that whether you are a natural reading lover like myself or merely read when you have to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First_article</title>
      <link>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/first_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:40:47 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hieudoan7.github.io/english/first_article/</guid>
      <description>LOL 24/05/2021 This is the first article to help Hd7 improve his active english skill, ie writing and speaking not just passive english skill such as listening and reading. Yeah here we go, everystep (though small) make a huge impact in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>